# Dobromir Marinov

Colchester, United Kingdom

(+44) 7599-943662 mr.d.marinov@gmail.com https://dmarinov.com/

# Personal profile

I am a software engineer with 3 years of professional experience. My main programming languages are Python and Java and my research interests lie in reinforcement learning, machine vision and software engineering. I am an EU citizen and I am eligible to work and study in the UK.

# **Employment**

#### **MSX** International

Software Engineer (Data science department)

Colchester, United Kingdom June 2018 – Present

- Building and maintaining machine learning models for predictive analytics in the automotive industry.
- Building microservices.
- Python, R, AWS, Docker, Nginx, Redshift, Exasol, LATEX.

#### **MSX** International

Software Developer

- Working in a team developing web applications.
- Java EE, SpringMVC, Liferay 6/7, Oracle, Jboss.
- PL/SQL, Hibernate, Freemarker, Gradle, Selenium.

Colchester, United Kingdom

November 2016 - June 2018

# StangaOne1

Web Development Intern

- Developing commercial websites.
- PHP, Laravel, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, JS, jQuery.

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

July 2016 - September 2016

## Education

# University of Essex

Colchester, United Kingdom

Digital and Technology Solutions (Software Engineer) (BSc) October 2016 - September 2019 (Expected)

Capstone Project: Developing algorithm for automatic hyperparameter optimisation and neural architecture search.

#### **Relevant Modules:**

- Software Engineering.
- Data Structures and Algorithms.
- Evolutionary Computation and Generic Programming.
- Advanced Programming.

# Big Data and Analytics Summer School

Delegate

- Learning Under Different Training and Testing Distributions.
- Visual recognition and tracking in large image and video datasets.
- Introduction to the Modelling and Analysis of Complex Systems.
- Artificial Intelligence and Neural Networks in Analytics.

## **High School of Mathematics**

Secondary education

• Program with extensive study of Mathematics, English and IT.

• Graduated with excellence: 5.93 out of 6.

Colchester, United Kingdom

July 2018 - August 2018

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

 $September\ 2011-June\ 2016$ 

# Awards and Certificates

#### Tech Industry Gold Certificate of Recognition

Tech Partnership Degrees

• Nominated by the University of Essex for outstanding academic achievements and awarded by the Tech Partnership Degrees.

 $London,\ United\ Kingdom$ 

 $June\ 2019$ 

#### General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

Certificate of attainment

Colchester, United Kingdom

 $April\ 2019$ 

#### **Information Security**

Certificate of attainment

 $Colchester,\ United\ Kingdom$ 

 $April\ 2019$ 

## The Degree Apprenticeship Prize

University of Essex

• Awarded to the 2<sup>nd</sup> year apprenticeship degree student with the best overall mark.

Colchester, United Kingdom

September 2018

# K.F. Bowden Memorial Prize

University of Essex

• Awarded to the top 4 first year students, in CSEE, with the best overall year mark.

Colchester, United Kingdom

September 2017

#### Award of Excellence

**High School of Mathematics** 

Plovdiv, Bulgaria June 2016

• Awarded for overall performance above 5.80 out of 6.

### StangaOne1 Academy

Web Development Basics

Plovdiv, Bulgaria January 2016 - May 2016

• PHP 5, MySQL, Git, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, HTML 5, CSS 3.

# Extracurricular activity

# Course Representative (1st and 2nd year)

University of Essex

Colchester, United Kingdom October 2016 - June 2018

• Representing and supporting students on the course and in the department.

#### German 1 and 2

University of Essex

Colchester, United Kingdom

# October 2016 - April 2018

#### Colchester Zoo Volunteer

University of Essex

Colchester, United Kingdom July 2017 - September 2017

#### HackEssex 2017

University of Essex

- 24 hours hackathon. • Eye tracking software integrated into a website.
- Selected as one of the top 3 best projects out of 20 competing.

# Colchester, United Kingdom

April 2017

#### UNESCO Project for an educational game

University of Essex

- Main programmer.
- Made using Unity.

Plovdiv, Bulgaria

January 2015 - September 2016